独在
大海
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
右翼部鸣明
校对
牙牙/Husky
特效
presisco
压制
时间轴 SG presisco 文本处理 谷子 yoyo
资源搬运 yoyo 特别参考帮助 考生 09
史蒂文 我已经快猜到这个惊喜是什么了
I'm starting to guess the surprise, Steven.
我跟你说了要闭上眼睛噢
I told you to close your eyes!
不好意思
Sorry.
好了 在这等着
Okay, wait here!
萨普莱斯!
Surprise!
我们买了一艘船!
We bought a boat!
呃 纠正一下 --我们租了一艘船
Uh, correction --We rented a boat.
我虽然现在是暴富了 但是买一艘船
I may be rich, but buying a boat would be going
未免也太过了
a bit overboard.
就是一个我从水手们那学的笑话啦
Just a joke I picked up from some sailors.
他们的幽默感总是令人惊讶
They have a surprisingly clean sense of humor.
史蒂文 这是谁啊
Steven,who is this?
呃 葛雷格·宇宙
Uh,Greg Universe.
你曾经弄断我的腿 试着利用海洋
You broke my leg trying to use the ocean
飞回你的母星
to fly back to your homeworld.
这里青金石壁琉璃 很高兴认识你
Lapis Lazuli. Nice to meet you.
很好 那么 我要去启动这艘船了
Great! Well,I'll get the boat started.
那么你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
这很好了 史蒂文
It's nice, Steven...
但是 我不确定自己是怎么考虑的
but I don't know.
青金石 我知道你和铁石英
Look, Lapis, I know you spent a really long time fused
在海底融合了相当久
with Jasper at the bottom of the ocean,
但是你现在已经不再是孔雀石了
but you're not Malachite anymore.
而水是你自身的一部分
And water is a part of who you are.
你不能因为一次糟糕的经历就放弃这部分
You can't let one bad experience take that away from you.
不止一次
It was more than one.
就当只是尝试好了
Just give it a chance.
我发誓你会感到前所未有的乐趣
I promise we'll make this the most fun you've ever had.
史蒂文 我...不配拥有这些
Steven,I...don't deserve this.
你当然配了!
Of course you do!
我们甚至给这艘船命名为小琉璃号
We even named her Li'l Lappy.
好吧 我会尝试一下的
Okay. I'll give it a chance.
但是 就一下
But, just one.
你们两个准备好启程了吗
You two ready to set sail?
是的 船长!
Aye, aye, Captain!
是的
Yes.
全速前进--
Full speed ahe--
哎呀 你觉得会有人发现吗
Ah, geez, you think anyone will notice?
喔啊 我想我真的重创了那个码头
Wow, I think I did a number on that dock.
也许其他人应该试试当船长
Maybe somebody else should take a shot at being captain.
你怎么看 青金石船长?
What do you say, Captain Lazuli?
我不该当
I shouldn't.
上嘛 青金石
Go for it, Lapis.
不要把控制权给我!
Don't put me in charge!
噢 对不起
Oh, sorry.
我是说 我-我不懂驾船的事
I mean, y-you shouldn't trust me with the boat.
呃 没关系 不用困扰
Uh, that's okay. Don't worry about it.
我们可以都当大副 这样就没有竞争压力了
We can all be first mates so there's no pressure.
今天只能用来嗨!
Only fun stuff today!
青金石 如果你想的话还是可以戴这顶帽子的
Lapis, you can still wear the hat, if you want.
谢谢 但是我不想让那东西戴在我身上
Thanks, but I'm not putting that on my body.
让我们嗨起来 --
Let's set a course for f-u-u-un!
老爹 老爹
Dad! Dad!
嘿 你们俩终于玩腻那个喇叭了?
Hey, you two. Finally get enough of that horn?
啥
What?!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
钓鱼
Catching fish.
噢 我来帮忙
Oh, I can help!
什么鬼?!!?
What the?!
这确实是一种 呃 非常拽的钓鱼法
That's a pretty uh...fancy way of catching fish.
那是因为青金石超厉害的!
That's 'cause Lapis is supa' strong!
我 呃 感谢你的好意
Well, I, uh, appreciate the gesture,
但是我觉得坚持用
but I-I think it would be safer to stick
传统的方法比较安全
to the old-fashioned way of doing it.
噢 呃...当然
Oh, uh...sure.
哇 青金石 那太了不起了
Wow, Lapis!That was ama...zing...
那么 你们传统的方法是怎么样的
So, how do you fish the old-fashioned way?
噢 非常简单
Oh, it's pretty simple.
你先准备一根钓鱼竿
You start with a rod,
在鱼线末端绑上一个钩子
and you put a hook on the end of your line.
然后 当你感觉到鱼咬钩了
And then,when you feel a nibble,
你就收线把它拉上来
you reel it in.
就这样
And there it is.
你给自己钓了一条鱼来吃!
You've caught yourself a fish to eat!
但是鱼为什么要咬钩
But why would a fish ever bite a hook?
你要放上鱼饵
You got to bait it --put something on it
你知道鱼喜欢什么 像虫子或者20刀的纸币之类的
you know it wants,like a worm or a $20 bill.
来 我示范给你看
Here, I'll show you.
钓鱼
Fishing.
上钩的那一部分要什么时候开始
When does the fish part happen?
有些时候 钓鱼的意义不在于渔获多少
Well, sometimes it isn't about the fish you keep,
而在于你与身边的人共度的好时光
but the company you catch.
哇 鱼咬钩了!
Whoa!I got a bite.
青金石 来试试
Lapis, here!Give it a try!
就像那样拿着竿然后收线
Hold it just like that and reel it in slowly.
像这样?
Like this?
完全没错 看起来是条大鱼!
You got it. It looks like a big one!
青金石
Lapis!
史蒂文
Steven!
你能做到的 青金石
You got it, Lapis!
把它钓上来
Reel it in!
它...拽的...力气好大!
It's...pulling...so hard!
看来租鱼竿
Looks likethis pole rental turned
得变成买鱼竿了
into a pole purchase.
但是你在与那野兽的斗争中非常给力
But you did a great job tangling with that beast.
是-是啊
Y-Yeah.
不用为没钓上的那条鱼失落
Don't worry about that one getting away.
噢 谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
好吧 今天我的冒险任务也到上限了
Welp, that's my adventure quota for the day.
我去驾驶室 有什么事找我就吆喝一声
I'll be at the controls. Holler if you need me.
是 长官 青金石 你...
Yes, sir!Lapis, what do you...
青金石?
Lapis?
嘿 你在干什么呢
Hey. Whatcha doing?
我只是觉得我需要坐一会儿
I just thought I'd sit for a bit.
在鱼竿折断之前 你看起来
You looked like a real pro fisher
简直是个钓鱼行家
before the pole snapped.
谢谢
Thanks.
钓鱼确实扫兴了点
So, fishing was a bust.
但是我们还有其他的项目可以嗨
But I-I got something that'll cheer you up.
沙壶球
Shuffleboard!
你怎么看
What do you say?
刚才怎么了
What was that?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事 怎么了
Yeah. What's going on?
史蒂文 你可以过来一下吗
Steven!You got a moment?
都没事吧 大副老爹
Is everything okay,First Mate Dad?
嘘 你听到了吗
Shh!You hear that?
呃 没有
Uhhh...no.
船好像停下了
I guess it stopped.
我想船应该是哪里坏了
I think something's wrong with the boat.
啊天哪 舵叶被卡住了
Aw, geez, something's throwing off the rudder.
我不知道现在是什么情况
I don't know what's going on,
使用指南也没有用
and this owner's manual is no help.
那上面基本上是关于日光浴
It's mostly advice on sun tanning
还有鱼子酱要配什么饼干的建议
and what crackers go with caviar.
那鱼子酱要配什么饼干?
Well, what crackers go with caviar?
水饼干
Water crackers.
就是这个声音
There it is.
诶玛 我的引擎啊
Oh, crud!The engine!
我可不懂怎么修引擎
I don't know how to fix an engine.
这次旅程可能要多耽误一会儿了
This trip might be a Little longer
我的小伙计
than we thought,little buddy.
格雷格的话出自经典电视剧"Gilligan's Island"(格里甘岛),其中Skipper喜欢戴船长帽并称呼主角为little buddy
青金石
Lapis?
呃 我有些不那么好的消息
Um...I have some not-so-good news.
引擎出了问题
There's trouble with the engine,
我们可能要在海上困一阵子了
and we might be stuck out here for a while.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry!
这都是我的错
This whole thing is my fault.
我只想让你开心 但是现在一切都搞砸了
I just wanted you to have fun. but e-everything's a mess.
早知道我不应该拉你来的
I shouldn't have made you come on this trip.
这是我的错 我才应该被怪罪
It's my fault. I'm the one to blame.
不是的
That's not true.
我真的努力试着享受这次旅行
I'm really trying to enjoy it out here, but...
但是我无法停止回忆融合成孔雀石的时候
I can't stop thinking about being fused as Malachite,
我是如何把她困在海底
how I used all my strength to hold her down in the ocean,
又是如何努力对抗铁石英
and how I was always battling against Jasper
让她不能与我分开
to keep her bound to me.
但是现在不再是这样了
But it's not like that anymore.
你不用和铁石英在一起了
You don't have to be with Jasper.
那不是重点 我 --
That's not it. I --
我想她了
I miss her.
啥?!
What?!
我们融合太久了
We were fused for so long.
但是...她很坏
But...she's terrible.
我才是更坏的那个 我已经做了很多坏事
I'm terrible! I did horrible things!
我-我弄断了你爸爸的腿 我盗走了你们地球上的海水
I-I broke your dad's leg. I stole Earth's ocean!
继续 继续反驳我啊
Go on!Tell me I'm wrong!
终于啊
Finally!
铁石英
Jasper!
我还以为我再也赶不上你了
I thought I'd never catch up to you!
你一直在跟踪我们?
You've been following us?
我只是在跟踪你
I've been following you.
退后
Stay back!
现在你终于打算用盗版玫瑰的技能了?
This dulled-down version of Rose Quartz works for you now?
你的盾不应该指向我
You're pointing that shield the wrong way.
她才是你应该害怕的人
She's the one you should be afraid of.
你说的不对
That's not true.
你可骗不了我
You can't lie to me.
我已经见识过你的力量了
I've seen what you're capable of.
我以为我已经很残暴了 但是你 --
I thought I was a brute, but you --
你简直是怪物
you're a monster.
我...
I...
青金石不想再与你有任何瓜葛了
Lapis doesn't want anything to do with you!
这是我们...
This is between...
两个人之间的事!
us!
史蒂文!
Steven!
请再次与我融合吧
Let's be Malachite again.
为什么...你要这么做
Why...would you want that?
我之前对融合的观念完全是错的 但是你让我理解了
I was wrong about fusion. You made me understand!
孔雀石比我们两个都更强 更大
Malachite was bigger and stronger than both of us!
我们能上天!
We could fly!
青金石 别听她的
Lapis, don't listen to her!
少管闲事!
Stay out of this!
我之前对你很坏
I was terrible to you.
我喜欢夺取你的一切
I liked taking everything out on you.
但是我必须这么做 我- 我讨厌你
I needed to. I-I hated you.
我们的融合太糟糕了
It was bad!
这次不会再是那样了 我已经改变了
It'll be better this time. I've changed.
你已经改变了我
You've changed me.
只有我才可以驾驭你这样的力量
I'm the only one who can handle your kind of power.
我们在一起将无人能挡
Together,we'll be unstoppable!
我拒绝
No.
什么
What?
我们这样的关系是不健康的
What we had wasn't healthy.
我从来没喜欢过跟你在一起的感觉 我跟你再也不可能了
I never want to feel like I felt with you -- never again!
你走吧
So just go.
-青金石 -她已经说拒绝了
-Lapis! -She said, "No"!
不要纠缠她了
Leave her alone!
这全是你的错
This is your fault.
我要灭了你
I'll shatter you!
青金石 你做到了
Lapis, you did it!
你们俩没事吧
Are you two okay?!
啥
What?!
刚才发生了啥
What happened?
呃 说来话长
Uh, it's kind of a long story.
我想最后我还是得买那船
I guess I bought a boat after all.
呃 对不起 老爹
Ehh, sorry, Dad.
不过 嘿 从这上面看海倒是挺美的
But, hey, the ocean's really beautiful from up here.
是啊
Yeah.
确实
It is.